■
本剧集字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译制作
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再整理而成
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
天哪
Oh, my God.
翻译：木浅薰   萨萨   wdjmhs
翻译：CS小明漫画家   Michael   米苏
时间轴：加森    密斯恩  wsr
校对：木浅薰    妖月Seraphim
后期：渔夫
字幕总监制：妖月Seraphim
求你  救救我
Please... help me.
求你  救救我  拜托
Please... help me. Come on.
撑住
Hang on.
天哪
Oh, my God.
我的神
救救我  丁甘  池塘里有东西
Help me! Dingaan! Dingaan! There's something in the pond!
救命
Help!
-丹妮  丹妮  -丁甘  救救我
- Denny! Denny?! - Dingaan! help me!
别离开我们
Don't leave us!
把它弄走
Get it off me!
把它弄走  神啊
Get it off me! God! God!
又出现了  刚才是每60秒一次
There it is again. Used to be every 60 seconds.
现在是每10秒一次了
Now it's every 10.
拿走吧  请自便
There you go. Help yourself.
你已经习惯如此了是吗
You're getting pretty good at that.
都24小时了  爸和亚蕾克西应该到了
It's been 24 hours. Dad and Lexi should be there by now.
我们就专心管好自己的任务吧
Let's stay focused on our job.
如果会有袭击
If there's gonna be an attack,
应该很快就会有了
it's bound to happen pretty soon.
做好准备
Keep your dukes up.
你太着急了  不要勉强
You're pushing. Don't force it.
瞄准心脏
Aim for the heart.
记住  当你遇到紧急情况
Now, remember, when you're in a situation
却又没有枪时  你只有一次机会
where you don't have a gun, you only get one chance.
再来一次
Try again.
正中靶心
Bull's-eye!
你觉得
Do you think...
因此哈尔才给爸那个毒液注射器吗
that's why Hal gave dad the syringe... with the poison?
什么注射器
What syringe?
就是爸和亚蕾克西上飞船前  他...
You know, before he got on the ship with Lexi, he --
只是以防万一
just in case.
我以为你知道呢
I thought you knew.
你父亲也同意带了
And your dad agreed to take it?
是的
Yeah.
干得好  马特
Good work, Matt.
-这次真准  正中靶心呢  -谢谢
- That was unbelievable...bull's-eye. - Thanks.
我们去巡视一下防御带附近
Let's check the perimeter.
站岗要小心
Hey, be careful on your watch out there.
丁甘的侦察队
Dingaan's recon team
只是去侦查方圆三公里的范围
was only supposed to scout a two-mile radius.
他也该回来了
He should be back by now.
而且迟归的还不止他们一队
And they're not the only squad overdue.
安东尼小队一小时前就该回来了
Anthony's team was supposed to be back over an hour ago.
希望他们没有遇上那个
Well, let's just hope they didn't meet up
爱用火刑的被烧焦的领主吧
with that scorched overlord with the burn-torture fetish.
丁甘应该多带点人  那个白痴
Dingaan should have taken more people. Idiot.
丁甘
Whoa, whoa, Dingaan!
你没事吧
Hey, you okay?
你巡逻队剩下的人呢
Where's the -- where's the rest of your patrol?
都死了
They're gone.
他们都死了
They're all gone.
陨落星辰
第四季第十二集
[本季终]
"发生了什么并不重要
"It's not what happens to you
重要的是你选择了如何应对"
but how you choose to react that matters."
自动驾驶锁定了归航信标
Autopilot's latched onto the homing beacon.
不管艾士芬尼的能量核在月亮上的哪里
Wherever the Espheni's power core is on the moon,
我们都在径直飞向那里
we're heading straight for it.
好的  我去检查一下炸弹
All right. I'm gonna check the bombs.
糟糕
Oh, no.
船体受损了
The breach in the hull.
肯定是我们休眠时  温度过低
The temperature must have caused the bomb casings to crack
-导致炸弹壳体破损  -我只能
- while we were in stasis. - I had to turn
关掉生命维持系统来保证供能
off life support to preserve power.
我并不知道
I didn't know that --
什么  不知道这会毁掉炸弹吗
What? That it would destroy the bomb?
我想应该还有别的解释吧
Oh, I'm sure there's another explanation.
你不会认为我是故意弄坏它的吧
You don't think I sabotaged it.
你还是不信任我吗
You still don't trust me?
我信任你  亚蕾克西  我选择了信任你
No, I trust you, Lexi. That's my choice.
但现在的重点不在于我是否信任你
But trust isn't really the issue right now.
重要的是我们得炸掉能量核...
We have to blow up the power core...
但我们没炸弹了
and we don't have a bomb.
不不  等等  不是这样的
Well, no, no, no. Hold on. I-it doesn't work that way.
我不是个破坏机器
I'm not a doomsday device.
拜托  亚蕾克西
Come on, Lexi.
我亲眼见过你连指头都没动
I saw you wipe beamers out of the sky
就让一艘激光飞船坠毁了
without even lifting a finger.
我是靠集中精力
What I do relies on concentration,
像重力一样指挥我周围的自然能量
directing the natural forces around me like gravity,
这在真空中没有用
which doesn't work in this vacuum.
那等我们靠近了月球表面
Okay, well, when we get closer to the lunar surface,
你不能用月球的重力吗
you can't use the moon's gravity?
也许我会变强一点  但...
I mean, I might get a little bit stronger, but --
-不一样吗  -不一样
- Wouldn't be the same? - No.
那就是我们的目标吗
Is that our target?
是的
Yes.
它集采矿平台  冶炼厂和
It's a mining platform, refinery, and energy plant
能源动力厂为一体
all in one.
-以有效利用氦-3  -这帮混蛋
- To deploy helium-3. - Son of a bitch.
原来是这么一回事
So that's it, huh?
它们从月岩中提取氦-3
So they extract the helium-3 from the lunar rock
-以矿石作为燃料源  -没错
- and then use the ore as a fuel source. - Exactly.
它们把矿石冶炼成能源
They refine the ore into energy
再传输到能量核
and deliver it to the power core,
转换成无线电力
which converts it into wireless electricity
发射到地球上去
and beams it to the Earth.
无线电力
Wireless electricity.
特斯拉说过这是可行的
Tesla said it was possible.
所以它们是这么做的
So that's how they do it.
它们的一切设施都是这样供能的
That's how they power everything...
所有的集中营电网  械甲怪和激光飞船
All the ghetto walls and the Mechs and the Beamers.
把人类变成迅猎兽用的都是这能源
That's how they're turning humans into Skitters.
是的  所有需要驱动的战争机器
Yes. Everything they need to fuel their war machine.
艾士芬尼会选择侵略地球绝非偶然
I mean, it's no accident that the Espheni chose Earth.
它们需要一个有富含氦-3接近月球
They need a life-sustaining planet
且能维持生命的活体星球
close to a helium-rich moon.
被我烧伤的领主说过
That overlord that I burned,
危险即将来临
he said that there was a danger coming,
一种我们无法理解的力量
a force that we couldn't comprehend.
怎么回事
What the hell?
有人试图修改我们的归航信标
Something's overriding our homing beacon,
让我们偏离原定轨道
pulling us off course.
它们发现我们了
They're onto us.
看不到月亮了
The moon is in the dark.
我不会坐以待毙的
I'm not gonna stand here and wait.
跟在我后面
Get behind me.
拜托  赶紧把东西炸掉
Blow something up, would you, please?
然后快点回来
And hurry back home.
我们在树林深处遇见一个自卫队营地
We came upon a militia camp deep in the woods.
像是被废弃了  我派迪克和丹妮
Seemed abandoned, so I sent Dick and Denny to fan out,
分头侦查
check around.
当时能见度很低
I-it was hard to see.
四周都被浓雾笼罩
There was a thick layer of fog everywhere.
接着我才突然意识到为何一片寂静
But then I realized why it was so quiet.
因为士兵都倒在了地上
Soldiers were all on the ground.
有东西在他们胸前震动
They had these things pulsating on their chests.
有人还在抽搐
S-s-some of the people were convulsing,
像是在转化成别的生物
tra-transforming into something else.
不一会儿  他们甚至都无力尖叫了
After a while, they weren't even screaming.
我想帮忙  但他们都被困住了
I-I-I tried to help, but they were stuck somehow,
被困在地上的类似柏油的东西中
trapped in some kind of tar on the ground.
有个人看向我  直视我的双眼
One of them looked at me, right into my eyes.
那是饥肠辘辘的野兽看猎物的眼神
It was like how a hungry animal looks at its prey.
于是我逃跑了
That's when I started to run.
我没法救他们了
I couldn't save them.
如果你不跑  你也会死
You'd be dead, too, if you didn't run.
毫无疑问  那些是人类迅猎兽
Human Skitters. There's no question.
我和亚蕾克西在一块时看见过它们这么干
Saw them working on this when I was with Lexi that,
看来它们现在已经不用把我们
I guess, they don't have to drag us off
拖到工厂去转化了
to some factory to mutate us anymore.
可以就地让我们变身怪物
They can just drop it right in our laps.
在我们地盘上把我们变成迅猎兽
They're turning us into Skitters on our own turf.
你在那儿还看见谁了吗
You see anyone else there?
你是说莎拉吗
You mean Sara?
我不是这个意思
That's not what I asked.
这方向上一路没有人迹
Nothing headed in this direction.
目前而已
For Now.
好了  别絮絮叨叨了
All right, ladies.
睡前故事到此为止
Let's wrap up the bedtime story.
-好  -敌人知道我们的位置
- All right. - The enemy knows our location.
丁甘看见的怪物可能就在向我们这边而来
Whatever Dingaan saw could be headed this way.
我们有一半人在执行侦察任务
half our people are out on reconnaissance.
已经够分散了
We're spread thin as it is.
所有人回到自己的岗位上  保持警惕
Everybody should get to their posts. Be on alert.
走吧
Let's go.
你看见的那个人
That guy you saw...
他真的被困住了  不能动弹吗
was he really stuck like that? He-he couldn't move?
没事的  马特  不要慌
It's okay, Matt. We're not gonna panic.
不管敌人是什么  我们都有万全准备
Whatever's out there, we're ready for them.
对吧
Right?
是的  上校
Colonel.
走吧  孩子
Let's go, boy.
你真的觉得我们可以只当朋友
You really think we can just be friends?
如果这是我唯一的选择  是的
If that's my only option, yeah.
你一直都是我最好的朋友  玛吉
You've always been my best friend, Maggie.
所以这才如此艰难
That's why it's so tough.
有激光飞船来了  我们得赶紧逃
Incoming beamer. We need to get the hell out of here.
他妈的  老子再也不要一味防守了
Screw that. No way am I playing defense anymore!
你不明白
You don't understand.
小心  小心  有东西被抛下来了
Look out! look out! Incoming!
我们快回去吧
Let's get back!
-别挡路  伙计  -不  快离开
- Clear some space, guys! - No, let's get out of here, man.
哈尔  玛吉  快跑
Hal, Maggie, run!
哈尔  别愣着  快跑
Hal, stop staring. Run.
快跑
Let's go.
快跑  快跑  快跑
Whoa! go! go! go! go! go!
快点  到上边来
Come on! Up here!
赶快
Hurry up!
快走  快走
Go! go! go! go! go! go! go!
赶快
Hurry up!
加油  哈尔  赶快
Come on, Hal. Hurry.
怎么了  为什么停下
What's wrong? Why are you stopping?
真的假的啊  我们被粘住了
Are you kidding me? We're stuck.
好像是胶水
It's like cement.
耶和华是我的牧者  我必不至缺乏
The lord is my shepherd. I shall not want.
他使我躺卧在青草地上
He maketh me to lie down in greener pastures.
他引领我
He leadeth me.
我虽然行过死荫的幽谷
Yea, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death,
也不怕遭害  你的杖...
I will fear no evil: for thou art with --
离门远点  马特
Get away from the door, Matt.
我们得把这些窗户封住
We're gonna have to barricade these windows.
别让雾气渗透进来  伙计
Keep that fog from seeping in here, buddy.
好的
Okay.
好的  我们能行的
Here we go. We got it.
很好  继续
Good. Keep going.
马特  过来
Matt, come over here.
别让那玩意碰到你  马特
Don't let that stuff touch you, Matt.
快跑  快跑
Run. Run!
你真以为劫持我们的飞船
Did you really think you could hijack our ship?
还能瞒过我吗
And I wouldn't know about it?
米拉  你怎么...
Mira, what are you...
我的天呐
Oh, my god.
我等待这一刻很久了  梅森
I've waited a long time for this, Mason,
我会尽情享受的
and I'm going to enjoy it.
是他
Oh, no. It's him.
别碰她
Don't you touch her.
不
No!
我用不着碰到她
I don't have to touch her.
别捡了  别捡了
Leave it! leave it! leave it!
我的枪
My gun!
别管它了
Forget it.
我被粘住了
I'm stuck.
我的胳膊不能动了  还有腿
I can't move my arms, my legs.
我也是
Neither can I.
不要啊  不要
Oh, no! oh, no! no!
安
Anne!
安  离那雾气远一点
Anne! stay out of the fog!
安  不要接触那雾气
闭嘴  珀普
Shut up, Pope!
别吸引它们的注意了
Stop attracting them.
救命  我被困住了
Help! I'm stuck!
我们在雾气里
We're in the fog!
救命
Help!
韦弗上校
Colonel weaver?
在这里  不过动不了了
Yeah, right here. I just can't seem to move.
等等
Wait.
它们一定会进来的
I think they're gonna come in here.
进来抓我们  我有预感
They're gonna get us. I... know it.
我们屁都预感不到  马特
We don't know a damn thing, Matt.
尽力挺住
Just hang tight.
我不会让你出事的
I'm not gonna let anything happen to you.
我看到了工厂里情景
I saw it happen at the factory.
它们会进来抓我们  然后把我们变成...
They're gonna get us and change us into these --
停下  马特  停下
Stop. Matt, stop.
不要  不要  不要
No. No, no, no!
那把刀  还在你手里吗
The knife -- you still got it?
-是的  还在  -拿出来
- Yeah. Yeah, I got it. - Get it out.
拿到了  拿到了
I got it. I got it.
瞄准心脏
Aim for the heart.
心脏  心脏在哪
The heart? Where's the heart?
赶快
Just do it!
正中靶心  马特  漂亮
Bull's-eye, Matt. Bull's-eye.
我兄弟意外死去之前
Before his untimely death,
实施了一个保险措施
my brother implemented a safeguard.
她身上的三曲枝图  意思不是和平
That triskelion she wears -- it doesn't mean "peace."
从来都不是
It never did.
意思是控制
It means "control."
玛吉  要行动就快点
Maggie? If you're gonna do something, you better do it now.
赶快行动
Do it faster than now!
本  把手给我
Ben! give me your hand.
玛吉  它们越来越近了
Maggie, they're getting close.
没用  没有支撑的东西
It's no use. There isn't any leverage.
加油  你可以的
Come on. You can do it.
你可以的  加油
You can do it! come on!
好样的
Attagirl.
我们俩一起才能救他
He's gonna need both of us.
-哈尔  -我随时准备着
- Hal! - Whenever you two are ready.
不  不不
No. No, no.
不要因为我而伤害她
Don't hurt her because of me.
不  不不
No. No, no.
安  别踏进浓雾
Anne! Stay out of the fog!
你闭上嘴行吗
Will you shut up?!
而且你干嘛一直叫她
Why do you keep calling for her, anyway?
她是营地边缘的前哨
She's a sentry on the outpost on the edge of camp.
我只希望她没被困在这倒霉玩意儿里
I'm just hoping she didn't get stuck in this crap.
要不是你不听我的警告  直接跑进来
We wouldn't be stuck if you hadn't run directly
我们也不会被困住
into the very thing I told you to run away from.
当你遇到未知危险的时候
Do you always go stampeding towards things
是不是只会一根筋冲进去
when you have no idea what the risk is?
是  算是吧
Yeah, kind of.
白痴
Idiot.
那是什么鬼东西
What the hell is that?
-什么东西  什么  -不不不
- What is it? What? Huh? - Oh, no, no, no.
什么情况
What the hell is happening?
-那是什么  -不不不
- What is it? - No, no, no.
-丁甘  - 别动  别动  -什么
- Dingaan... - Don't move. Don't move. - What?
别呼吸  别动
Don't even breathe! Don't move!
丁甘
Dingaan!
任何武器都有弱点
Every weapon has its weakness.
而我刚刚找到了你的克星
I just found your kryptonite.
我遵守了诺言  把他送到了这里
I delivered him here just like I promised I would.
我想证明自己对你的事业有多大价值
I wanted to prove how valuable I am to your cause.
你为什么要杀掉你最强大的武器呢
So why would you kill the best weapon you have?
就为了证明自己比他强大吗
To prove you're stronger than him?
我们扛不过去了  对吗
We're not gonna make it, are we?
马特  听着
Matt, listen to me.
我要你坚强起来  马特
I need you to stay tough, Matt.
你不能认输  有我在你就不能认输
You're not gonna throw in the towel, not on my watch.
听到了吗  战士  听到了吗
You hear what I'm saying, soldier? You hear me?
我要你跟我重复
I want you to repeat after me.
战斗不息  奉陪到底
The fight isn't over till it's over.
说
Say that.
战斗不息  奉陪到底
The fight isn't over till it's over.
很好  我们一起说
That's it. Now say it with me.
战斗不息  奉陪到底
The fight isn't over till it's over.
The fight isn't over till it's over!
继续说  战斗不息  奉陪到底
Keep chanting! the fight isn't over till it's over!
战斗不息  奉陪到底
The fight isn't over till it's over!
挺住伙计们  我来了
Hold on, boys. I'm coming.
战斗不息  奉陪到底
The fight isn't over till it's over!
说得太好了
Damn straight.
哈尔
Hal!
别打了  我们来救你
Stop firing. We got you.
什么  你们是在报税呢还是怎么的
Hey, what, are you guys filing taxes up there or what?
哈尔  听着  我们把电缆扔给你
Hal, listen, we're tossing you a cable.
你得信任我们
You're gonna have to trust us.
这些天你还真值得信任
'Cause it's so easy to trust you these days.
丁甘
Dingaan!
狗娘养的
Aah! You sons of bitches!
丁甘  丁甘
Dingaan! Dingaan!
把它弄走  把它弄走
Get it off me! Get this off me! Aah!
真不敢相信  我居然为你做了这种事
Ugh, I can't believe I just did that for you.
我们扯平了
We're even.
我这么做是为了整个艾士芬尼族
I did this for the Espheni Race.
这些人类...
These humans...
他们背叛了我  他们想杀我
They betrayed me. They tried to kill me.
我要烧死她  就像你烧我一样
I'm going to burn her just like you burned me.
我是艾士芬尼
I am Espheni!
保持清醒
Stay with me.
-你受伤了  -我没事
- You're hurt. - I'm okay.
我们得离开这里
We have to get out of here.
浪费了不少时间  我们的炸弹被毁了
Lost a lot of time. Our bomb is destroyed.
也许我们可以用这艘飞船当炸弹
Maybe we can use this ship as a bomb.
没错  只能这么做了
Yeah. That's the only way.
你能设置坐标
Can you set the coordinates
让它去撞击能量核吗
on a collision course for the power core?
能
Yeah.
是的  可以
Yes, I can.
但我需要你将激光飞船
But I'll need you to release the beamer
从激光牵引道上释放出去
from this ship's tractor beam,
否则它还是会被拖住
or it'll get dragged down, too.
我在这里无法做到
I can't do that from here.
在气闸里面  你会看到一个控制板
Inside the airlock, you'll find a panel.
你要毁掉里面的线路
You'll need to destroy the wires inside it.
这样就会启动激光飞船
That'll fire up the Beamer
等我过来时它就能发射了
so it's ready to go when I join you --
不不  我不能把你留在这
No, no. I'm not leaving you in here.
想要活着回去
We have to divide and conquer
我们就得分头行动
if we want to get out of this alive.
你说得对  这是唯一的办法
You're right. This is the only way.
我是你女儿  你现在应该相信我
I'm your daughter. It's time for you to trust me.
做出选择吧
Make your choice.
天哪
My God.
看来还是你赢了
I guess you won after all.
不  我能做到
No. I can do this.
在我道别以后
After I say goodbye.
放弃吧  你父亲的飞船没有回应
找到了  他距离...
父亲
爸爸
请听我说  我们需要您的帮助
有一些关于月球的事
我必须要告诉您
战斗不息  奉陪到底
The fight isn't over till it's over!
安
Anne!
我们得离开这
We need to get the hell out of here.
你确定你会用那玩意吗
Sure you know how to use that thing?
你还是不够了解我  丹
There's a lot about me you don't know, Dan.
是啊  看出来了
Yeah, I guess so.
-快点  -想要成功
- Hurry up! - If this is gonna work,
我们就要协力  配合好
we're gonna need to do it together... in tandem.
抓到以后  要抓紧了
When you feel it, grab it!
好的  赶紧扔下来
All right, just throw it!
好了吗  扔
Ready? Go!
好了
Okay!
谢谢你们
Thank you.
很高兴见到你们俩合作如此默契
It's great to see you two working so well together.
-你还好吗  -谢谢
- You okay? - Thank you.
乐意效劳  你还好吗  马特
Anytime. You okay, Matt?
让我烧死它
Let me burn it!
请便  弄死它
Be my guest. Get it.
-把它...  -没燃料了  该死
- Take... - I'm out! Damn it!
我被困住了
I'm stuck.
丹
Dan!
对不起
I'm so sorry.
希望这能有用
Hope this works.
喂  能听见我说话吗
Hello? Can you hear me?
亚蕾克西  你在干什么  我们得走了
Lexi, what are you doing?! We have to go!
你毁掉了跟踪波束的保护装置
You destroyed the tracking beam's security.
我在这里可以手动发射激光飞船
I can manually release the Beamer from here.
这很好  但你也要到激光飞船里来
Well, that's great, but you have to be in the Beamer with me.
我不能去
I'm not getting on the Beamer.
在你杀死领主前
The overlord destroyed the autopilot
它毁掉了自动驾驶系统
just before you killed him,
但我应该能够驾驶飞船飞向能量核
but I think I can command the ship towards the power core myself.
不不  肯定还有别的办法
No, no, no, no. There's got to be another way.
帮我个忙  碰一下那个茧
Do one thing for me. Touch the cocoon.
求你  这是唯一的办法
Please. This is the only way.
我们在用备用能量了  得抓紧时间
We're on reserve power. We have to hurry.
我不能维持太久
I can't maintain this for long.
听我说  我是你父亲
Listen to me. I'm your father,
你也不是什么都知道的
and you don't know everything.
-我要你按我说的去做  -我爱你
- I want you to do exactly what I'm telling you. - I love you.
我也很希望我们能在一起
And I so wish we could have been together
能听你的话  做你让我做的事
long enough to do what you tell me.
只是没有时间了
There just wasn't enough time.
听我说  这是我的错
Listen, this is my fault.
-如果我没让...  -这是唯一的办法
- If I hadn't asked... - It was the only way.
如果我们没有这么做  一切就都完了
If we hadn't done this, it would all be over.
你会失去你所爱的一切人和事
You would have lost everything and everyone you love with it.
不是所有人
Not everyone.
我为激光飞船设定了程序
I've programmed the Beamer.
它锁定了归航信标  可以返航了
It's locked onto the homing beacon to reverse course,
剩下的补给刚好够你回去
and there's just enough life support left to get you home.
但你现在就要离开
But you have to leave now.
不要这样
Don't do this.
谢谢你告诉我
Thank you for showing me
做人的意义
what it means to be a human being,
教会我如何去爱
for showing me how to love.
再见  爸爸
Goodbye, daddy.
那畜生请求支援了
The son of a bitch called in backup.
-丁甘  -怎么了
- Dingaan. - What is it?
- Dingaan. - What?!
别动
Don't move.
伙计们  很高兴跟你们一起玩
Folks, it's been a financial pleasure.
来吧
Come on.
你这个细条虫...
Aah, you slimy piece of --
谁啊
Who's there?!
安静  我觉得就是你把它们吸引过来了
Be quiet! I think you're attracting them!
莎拉
Sara?!
你还记得我名字  不错嘛
Well, you remember my name. That's something.
难以置信  没想到会这样重逢  宝贝
Unbelievable! It's quite the reunion, honey!
丁甘身上是什么东西
What is that thing on dingaan?
是人类生长激素培育的蚯蚓
That is a... an earthworm on human growth hormone.
拜托  干掉它
Please... just shoot it.
莎拉  行动之前先等一会儿
Sara, now, hold on one second before you do that.
不  听我说  亲爱的
No, listen. Listen, sweetheart.
扳机别扣得太用力  好吗
You don't want to squeeze the trigger too hard, all right?
轻轻的  明白吗  别太用力
Nice and easy, you understand? Don't squeeze the gun too hard.
轻一点  好吗
Take it easy. Okay!
别指手画脚  否则别怪我瞄准你
Let me do my thing, or I will shoot you on purpose!
放松  慢慢来
Easy! Just easy does it!
丁甘
Dingaan?
我没事
I'm good.
你来这里找我们  怎么没被困住
How did you find us without getting stuck?
我偷了辆车
I stole a four-wheel drive.
顺便说下  不用谢
You're welcome, by the way.
谢谢  感谢
Thank you? Thank you?
你就关心这个吗  你太不靠谱了
That's -- that's your concern? Well, you're unbelievable.
没问题  谢谢你
Here we go. Thank you.
你出现的时机真是太好了
You just show up at an incredibly convenient time.
然后呢  双膝跪地双手伏地
And what, we're supposed to get down on our hands and knees
往身上浇圣水吗
and wet ourselves?
谢谢你
Thank you!
别假装不想我
Don't act like you didn't miss me.
安  恐怕我现在不说就没机会了
Anne... if I don't get a chance to say it,
我只想告诉你  我为你感到非常自豪
I just wanted to tell you that I'm very proud of you.
你是个勇敢的女人
Okay... you're a brave woman.
你的坚韧是任何人无法比拟的
You've endured more than any -- any person has coming to them.
我尊敬你..
And I honor you...
作为女人...
as a woman...
战士...
as a soldier...
还有母亲...
and as a mom.
丹  丹  别说这种话
Oh, Dan. Dan, don't talk like that.
你现在不能放弃
You can't give up now.
我们要奉陪到底的啊
It's not over till it's over!
我没有
I'm not, uh...
谁说的  谁说我放弃了
Who said that? Who said I was giving up?
这些破玩意儿还不足以搞垮我
It's gonna take a lot more than this stupid thing.
-丹  -我来告诉你  告诉你
- Dan, Dan... - I'll tell you. I'll tell you. I'll tell...
一旦爸爸摧毁了能量源  也许...
Once dad destroys the power core, maybe...
外边的这些东西就会变成蝴蝶
Those things out here will turn into butterflies.
不会  但可以干扰制造雾气的东西
No, but it could affect whatever's causing this fog.
别放弃希望
Don't lose hope.
对  我们不能放弃希望
Yeah, no, we got to stay hopeful.
这些东西在干什么呢
Those things -- what are they doing?
听起来好像在从车两边往上爬
Sounds like they're trying to... climb up the side of the bus.
不是吧
No way.
你说什么来的
You were saying?
你还好吧  汤姆·梅森
Are you being okay, Tom Mason?
难以置信  你从哪儿冒出来的
I don't believe it! Where did you come from?!
这一切马上就要结束了
We'll be out of this situation directly.
谢谢你  科奇斯
Oh, thank you, Cochise.
你成功了  宝贝
You did it, baby.
汤姆·梅森  能听到我的声音吗
Tom Mason, can you hear me?
汤姆·梅森  我们要与你失联了
Tom Mason, we're losing contact with you.
拜托
Come on!
安  你没事吧
Anne? Are you okay?
雾散了
It's gone.
马特  你没事吧
Matt, are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
丹
Dan.
-丹  -小心
- Dan? - Look out!
丹  没事了
Dan, it's okay.
没事了  是我  安
It's okay. It's me -- Anne.
安
Anne?
-没事了  都过去了  -安
- It's okay. It's gone. - Anne...
没事了  都过去了
It's all right. It's gone.
上校  都结束了
Colonel, I-I-it's over.
马特
Matt.
给你
Here.
没错  孩子
That's right, son.
结束了
It's over.
我们居然...
Somehow...
挺过来了
we made it.
好
All right.
好  我们出去  看看情况如何
Yeah. Let's get out of here and see what's going on.
就这样了吗
So, that's it?
所有艾士芬尼的东西就这样停了吗
All the Espheni tech's gonna stop working just like that?
电网消失  大家都自由了吗
The ghetto walls are down? All those people are free?
那些还没有被艾士芬尼转化的都自由了
The ones who haven't been skitterized already.
我希望不管是怎么没电的
I just hope whatever gets unplugged
别太快  免得爸的激光飞船来不及回家
doesn't happen so fast dad's beamer can't make it home.
本  不确定因素还很多  好吗
Ben, we don't know what we don't know, all right?
马特
Matt!
-本  -你还好吗
- Ben! - You okay?
-很好  你呢  -我也是
- Yeah. Are you? - Yeah.
你真是选了个好时机重聚啊
You picked a hell of a time for a reunion.
是啊  你们有些人
Yeah, well, there's some of you
我似乎是躲不掉了
I just can't seem to keep my distance from.
看来他们炸掉了什么厉害玩意儿呢
Looks like they blew the hell out of something.
那就意味着他们很快就会回来了
Which means they'll be coming home soon.
也许还剩了些迅猎兽和械甲怪要杀
There still may be some Skitters and Mechs left to kill.
大家暂时不要放松警惕
Let's not let our guard down just yet.
因为你  我依旧在战斗
永远爱你的
安·梅森
Anne Mason.
科奇斯
Cochise.
我有汤姆和亚蕾克西的消息
I have news about Tom and Lexi.
我之前联系上了我的父亲
I was able to reach my father.
大部分沃尔姆飞船都回来了
The greater Volm have returned.
沃尔姆回来了
The Volm are back.
我爸爸呢
What about my dad?
恐怕他们的激光飞船
I'm afraid their beamer was...
被吹离了锁定的归航信标
blown from its homing-beacon lock.
是因为能量核的爆炸吗
The explosion from the power core?
没错  能量核被摧毁了
Correct. The power core was destroyed.
不过  当时还和艾士芬尼
However, there was a
进行了一场小规模战斗
skirmish with the Espheni.
汤姆和亚蕾克西的激光飞船
Tom and Lexi's beamer was
在我父亲的防护中幸免
spared by my father's defense,
但战斗结束时
but by the time the battle had finished,
他们的飞船就不见了
their ship was nowhere to be found.
我不明白
I don't understand.
沃尔姆没有搜寻他们吗
Are the Volm not out looking for them?
他们不是有技术能够...
I mean, don't they have the technology to --
他们当然还在继续寻找
They are looking for them, of course,
但宇宙是无限的
but space is not a finite environment.
就像在草堆中找一根针一样
It's like a needle in a haystack.
或者更准确一点  像大海捞针
Or more accurately, a needle in the ocean.
你说过激光飞船能够回来
You said the beamer could make it back.
你说过的...
You said...
马特  马特  马特
Matt! Matt! Matt! Matt, Matt, Matt!
-你说过...  -听我说  听我说
- You said -- - Hey. Hey, listen. Listen.
没事的
It's okay, buddy.
我们会找到他的
We're gonna find him.
我们会找到他
我可以肯定一件事...
If I know one thing for sure...
汤姆总能找到回来的路
Tom always finds his way home.
直到他回来之前...
And until he does...
我们必须得完成他未竟的事业
we have to finish what he started.
我们得结束这场战争
We have to end this war.
安东尼  你回来了
Anthony, you made it back.
是的
Yeah, I did.
有许多人没能回来
A lot of others didn't.
我很高兴你回来了
I'm glad you made it.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
我们还有些事情要做
Well, we got some work to do.
能量核被摧毁了
The power core's down.
现在是艾士芬尼不堪一击了
And the Espheni are sitting ducks for a change.
我们一起摧毁它们吧
Let's kick their ass.
你安然无恙
You are safe and sound.
-是谁  -我们为了和平而来
- Who's there? - We come in peace.
我们认为真理的不言而喻的
We hold these truths to be self-evident.
引自肯尼迪总统
我们唯一应该恐惧的是恐惧本身
The only thing we have to fear is fear itself.
引自罗斯福总统
敌人的敌人就是我的朋友
The enemy of my enemy is my friend.
快点现身
Show yourself.
汤姆·梅森
Tom Mason...
是时候了
It's about time.
我的天
Oh, my god.
我真没想到
I had no idea.
你...
You're...
你太美了
You're beautiful.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com